LUIZ MATTOS

Igmattos93@gmail.com • 437-985-3624 • linkedin.com/in/luizgsmattos/ • github.com/luizgmattos • Toronto, ON

SUMMARY

Junior Machine Learning graduated in Software Engineering – Artificial Intelligence with experience in developing models to perform image classification, and regression problems by applying multiple machine learning techniques throughout the process to deliver high quality results.

SKILLS & LANGUAGES

- Python, SQL, Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-Learn, Matplotlib, TensorFlow, NLTK, Seaborn, Power BI, Dashboards
- Fast learner, multi-tasker, interpersonal skills, great communication, emotional intelligence
- English, Portuguese, Spanish, French

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING - AI - CENTENNIAL COLLEGE

JAN 2021 - APR 2022

- 2+ years experience in developing code using Python to solve Machine Learning problems
- Delivered end-to-end projects on classification, prediction, recommender system applying multiple machine learning techniques to train, fine-tune, verify and extract valuable information from data
- Performed data cleaning and transformation in multiple projects to pass data through pipelines into models
- Used different ways to visualize and explain results through report: Matplotlib, Plotly, Seaborn, Power BI
- Implemented appropriate Machine Learning algorithms and tools to each individual case, identifying the best fit and parameters for each scenario through fine-tuning models
- Courses taken in the areas of: Math, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Supervised & Unsupervised Learning, Database (SQL), Software Development, Object Oriented Programing

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING - UNIVERSIDADE ESTÁCIO DE SÁ

MAR 2019 - MAR 2020

- Acquired strong project management skills in software engineering
- Studied metrics of software quality and standards, object-oriented programming, and system architecture following best practices when implementing software's

PETROLEUM ENGINEERING - UNIVERSIDADE ESTÁCIO DE SÁ

JAN 2013 - DEC 2017

- Acquired strong mathematical skills through courses: Linear Algebra, Calculus I, Calculus II, Calculus III, Physics, Statistics, Geophysics, Chemistry, Fluid Mechanics
- Developed geological knowledge with deposit evaluation, well logging, reservoir engineering

COURSES & CERTIFICATES

Congenial - Nitro - Data structures & Algorithms Intensive Training

Hashtag Treinamentos - Power BI, Python & SQL

Udemy - Machine Learning & Data Science Bootcamp 2022

Azimov - Data Visualization, Dash Boards, Data Science & Machine Learning

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MATH TUTOR - OXFORD LEARNING

NOV 2022 – PRESENT

- Tutoring kids and teenagers to better comprehend and apply mathematical concepts
- Identifying ways to communicate and acquire interest from student to learn and study

PETROLEUM ENGINEER - QUEIROZ GALVÃO

DEC 2014 - SEP 2016

 Collaborated with rig managers to control and deliver tasks with analytical data to best fit the company's work demand while assessing improvements in the workflow

PETROLEUM ENGINEER - SUBSEA7

APR 2014 - NOV 2014

- Assisted supply chain buyers to perform services with best prices and ensured time efficiency while analysing multiple requisitions
- Trained recently hired employees to perform new and ongoing work tasks